Usage: cli databases [options] [command]

(Legacy) The databases command allows you to create structured collections of documents and query and filter lists of documents.

Options:
  -h, --help                               display help for command

Commands:
  list [options]                           Get a list of all databases from the current Appwrite project. You can use the search parameter to filter your results.
  create [options]                         Create a new Database.
  
  list-transactions [options]              List transactions across all databases.
  create-transaction [options]             Create a new transaction.
  get-transaction [options]                Get a transaction by its unique ID.
  update-transaction [options]             Update a transaction, to either commit or roll back its operations.
  delete-transaction [options]             Delete a transaction by its unique ID.
  create-operations [options]              Create multiple operations in a single transaction.
  list-usage [options]                     List usage metrics and statistics for all databases in the project. You can view the total number of databases, collections, documents, and storage usage. The response includes both current totals and historical data over time. Use the optional range parameter to specify the time window for historical data: 24h (last 24 hours), 30d (last 30 days), or 90d (last 90 days). If not specified, range defaults to 30 days.
  get [options]                            Get a database by its unique ID. This endpoint response returns a JSON object with the database metadata.
  update [options]                         Update a database by its unique ID.
  delete [options]                         Delete a database by its unique ID. Only API keys with with databases.write scope can delete a database.
  list-collections [options]               Get a list of all collections that belong to the provided databaseId. You can use the search parameter to filter your results.
  create-collection [options]              Create a new Collection. Before using this route, you should create a new database resource using either a [server integration](https://appwrite.io/docs/server/databases#databasesCreateCollection) API or directly from your database console.
  get-collection [options]                 Get a collection by its unique ID. This endpoint response returns a JSON object with the collection metadata.
  update-collection [options]              Update a collection by its unique ID.
  delete-collection [options]              Delete a collection by its unique ID. Only users with write permissions have access to delete this resource.
  list-attributes [options]                List attributes in the collection.
  create-boolean-attribute [options]       Create a boolean attribute.
  
  update-boolean-attribute [options]       Update a boolean attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  create-datetime-attribute [options]      Create a date time attribute according to the ISO 8601 standard.
  update-datetime-attribute [options]      Update a date time attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  create-email-attribute [options]         Create an email attribute.
  
  update-email-attribute [options]         Update an email attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-enum-attribute [options]          Create an enum attribute. The `elements` param acts as a white-list of accepted values for this attribute. 
  
  update-enum-attribute [options]          Update an enum attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-float-attribute [options]         Create a float attribute. Optionally, minimum and maximum values can be provided.
  
  update-float-attribute [options]         Update a float attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-integer-attribute [options]       Create an integer attribute. Optionally, minimum and maximum values can be provided.
  
  update-integer-attribute [options]       Update an integer attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-ip-attribute [options]            Create IP address attribute.
  
  update-ip-attribute [options]            Update an ip attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-line-attribute [options]          Create a geometric line attribute.
  update-line-attribute [options]          Update a line attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  create-longtext-attribute [options]      Create a longtext attribute.
  
  update-longtext-attribute [options]      Update a longtext attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-mediumtext-attribute [options]    Create a mediumtext attribute.
  
  update-mediumtext-attribute [options]    Update a mediumtext attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-point-attribute [options]         Create a geometric point attribute.
  update-point-attribute [options]         Update a point attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  create-polygon-attribute [options]       Create a geometric polygon attribute.
  update-polygon-attribute [options]       Update a polygon attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  create-relationship-attribute [options]  Create relationship attribute. [Learn more about relationship attributes](https://appwrite.io/docs/databases-relationships#relationship-attributes).
  
  update-relationship-attribute [options]  Update relationship attribute. [Learn more about relationship attributes](https://appwrite.io/docs/databases-relationships#relationship-attributes).
  
  create-string-attribute [options]        Create a string attribute.
  
  update-string-attribute [options]        Update a string attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-text-attribute [options]          Create a text attribute.
  
  update-text-attribute [options]          Update a text attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-url-attribute [options]           Create a URL attribute.
  
  update-url-attribute [options]           Update an url attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  create-varchar-attribute [options]       Create a varchar attribute.
  
  update-varchar-attribute [options]       Update a varchar attribute. Changing the `default` value will not update already existing documents.
  
  get-attribute [options]                  Get attribute by ID.
  delete-attribute [options]               Deletes an attribute.
  list-documents [options]                 Get a list of all the user's documents in a given collection. You can use the query params to filter your results.
  create-document [options]                Create a new Document. Before using this route, you should create a new collection resource using either a [server integration](https://appwrite.io/docs/server/databases#databasesCreateCollection) API or directly from your database console.
  create-documents [options]               Create new Documents. Before using this route, you should create a new collection resource using either a [server integration](https://appwrite.io/docs/server/databases#databasesCreateCollection) API or directly from your database console.
  upsert-documents [options]               Create or update Documents. Before using this route, you should create a new collection resource using either a [server integration](https://appwrite.io/docs/server/databases#databasesCreateCollection) API or directly from your database console.
  
  update-documents [options]               Update all documents that match your queries, if no queries are submitted then all documents are updated. You can pass only specific fields to be updated.
  delete-documents [options]               Bulk delete documents using queries, if no queries are passed then all documents are deleted.
  get-document [options]                   Get a document by its unique ID. This endpoint response returns a JSON object with the document data.
  upsert-document [options]                Create or update a Document. Before using this route, you should create a new collection resource using either a [server integration](https://appwrite.io/docs/server/databases#databasesCreateCollection) API or directly from your database console.
  update-document [options]                Update a document by its unique ID. Using the patch method you can pass only specific fields that will get updated.
  delete-document [options]                Delete a document by its unique ID.
  list-document-logs [options]             Get the document activity logs list by its unique ID.
  decrement-document-attribute [options]   Decrement a specific attribute of a document by a given value.
  increment-document-attribute [options]   Increment a specific attribute of a document by a given value.
  list-indexes [options]                   List indexes in the collection.
  create-index [options]                   Creates an index on the attributes listed. Your index should include all the attributes you will query in a single request.
  Attributes can be `key`, `fulltext`, and `unique`.
  get-index [options]                      Get an index by its unique ID.
  delete-index [options]                   Delete an index.
  list-collection-logs [options]           Get the collection activity logs list by its unique ID.
  get-collection-usage [options]           Get usage metrics and statistics for a collection. Returning the total number of documents. The response includes both current totals and historical data over time. Use the optional range parameter to specify the time window for historical data: 24h (last 24 hours), 30d (last 30 days), or 90d (last 90 days). If not specified, range defaults to 30 days.
  list-logs [options]                      Get the database activity logs list by its unique ID.
  get-usage [options]                      Get usage metrics and statistics for a database. You can view the total number of collections, documents, and storage usage. The response includes both current totals and historical data over time. Use the optional range parameter to specify the time window for historical data: 24h (last 24 hours), 30d (last 30 days), or 90d (last 90 days). If not specified, range defaults to 30 days.
  help [command]                           display help for command
