Usage: cli databases create [options]

Create a new Database.


Options:
  --database-id <database-id>  Unique Id. Choose a custom ID or generate a
                               random ID with `ID.unique()`. Valid chars are
                               a-z, A-Z, 0-9, period, hyphen, and underscore.
                               Can't start with a special char. Max length is
                               36 chars.
  --name <name>                Database name. Max length: 128 chars.
  --enabled [value]            Is the database enabled? When set to 'disabled',
                               users cannot access the database but Server SDKs
                               with an API key can still read and write to the
                               database. No data is lost when this is toggled.
  -h, --help                   display help for command
